Next, let's do the hat.
Because the hat and the body are not intertwined,
we can directly anti-activate the body board,
and then individually activate the hat board.
In this way, the operation speed is faster.
Then the hat here,
in fact, we have a small function,
that is, sometimes the hat board we made
is not able to do it,
it is so close to the head,
it is so round,
it is very flat,
when we made the hat,
did I make this hat very flat?
Then my board is actually not intertwined.
Then why is the effect of my sewing
more close to the head than this?
Do you know which physical properties I adjusted?
Do you know what physical properties I adjusted?
Well, I guess you probably don't know,
because only friends who are serious about watching our physical properties teaching videos will know.
What kind of pressure?
How come there is pressure?
It's so funny.
Pressure is not a physical property.
In fact, it is a deformation.
It's a deformation.
I said it was the position of the seam line.
We are about to witness a miracle.
When we reduce the deformation rate to 100,
the wrinkles in the seam line position suddenly disappeared.
Isn't it amazing?
Because when a fabric deformation rate is,
how to say,
I try to tell you in a simple way,
the simplest method is that
when you adjust the deformation rate to 100,
the wrinkle effect of the seam line position will disappear.
If you want me to explain it to you seriously,
it's like this.
It's not that the deformation rate is 100.
That is to say,
a fabric,
the property of its wrinkle position
is different from the property of the flat fabric.
Because the wrinkle position has a lot of different kinds of forces,
forming a wrinkle.
The position of the wrinkle is like a small mountain,
and then the flat surface is like a flat surface.
The properties of the small mountain are different from the properties of the flat surface.
How to control it?
It is controlled by the deformation rate.
When the deformation rate is 0,
it will force all the small mountains and all the flat surfaces to be the same soil,
the same physical properties.
But if your deformation rate is 100,
it will require all the small mountains and all the flat surfaces
to start deforming.
It's easy to deform.
It's very easy to deform.
And then,
because our deformation rate is 0,
the wrinkle intensity of the fabric will become very, very low.
All the small mountains will be flat.
You can understand it like this.
100% of the small mountains will be flat.
If the deformation rate is 0,
all the small mountains will not deform,
and all the wrinkles will become more obvious.
I will simply explain to you what this is.
Now we have a board.
Let's assume that this board looks like this.
Let's freeze it.
And then we still have a small mountain.
This is a small mountain.
Then we still have a board that is sewn together with it.
There are many wrinkles below.
So,
is it possible to make clothes that are not easy to detatch when making a natural look?
If you transform it into a green and set it to 100,
when you set it to 0,
all the wrinkles will be there.
Then there is a mode that is 80,
which is the default mode.
80 80
you will feel that it will have some shaking, but it is not much different
because it has not changed yet, it is 100% so obvious
100% of the time, all the褶皱 will apply the original bending intensity times the deformation intensity
so your deformation intensity is 0
it is equivalent to your bending intensity, all the bending intensity of the褶皱 position
from 14 times 0, 37 times 0, 17 times 0, all times 0
if it is all 0, is it very soft, it has no bending intensity at all
and it is the褶皱 position, it will not affect this large piece of position
it will only affect this very fine, very fine褶皱
so you see, when I set the deformation intensity to 100
the most obvious, the most intuitive
effect is that your sewing line position becomes very flat
but the褶皱 of your other position is also very fine, very soft, understand?
so everyone must pay attention to this deformation intensity
not the deformation intensity, the deformation rate
is not to set it to 100
because if you set it to 100, it will be weakened very badly
unless you must have this special effect
for example, like our hat
I don't need it to have a褶皱
because this kind of wool hat
in fact, its褶皱 is not obvious
then you set it to 100, the deformation rate is not important
it doesn't matter
ok, ok, let's look at another question here
like this edge, we also set the deformation rate to 100
when the deformation rate is 100, it is very, very easy to deform
which leads to this edge, it will curl
there will be a problem
because it is easy to deform
super easy to deform
so at this time we are going to apply another fabric to it
just this edge
we can't let it deform so easily
see?
we can't let its deformation rate be 100
if it is 100, it will have the same problem as before
so we fold this edge and the hat itself
and use a different fabric
do you understand?
you still need to maintain its current
certain
maintain its current effect
in fact, everyone
even if you don't understand, it doesn't matter
you will know by looking at the actual effect
and
because our default fabric
is the most suitable for simulation
and the most stable kind of fabric physics
so
once you find
there is a problem with your fabric
or it doesn't look good
you just change it to the default fabric
and then start from the beginning
to see where the problem is
do you understand?
ok
now let's go back to the shoes
this should be to change the shoes
it is our foot
before long long ago
we shrink the foot
into a narrow board
to make it easier to wear boots
now
we have to
before wearing boots
first add a fixing pin
and then
fix all the foot panels
to the ankle of the simulation model
ok
otherwise
if you wear boots
then you use this fixing pin
to fix the simulation model
it may identify the boots
because its point is
according to which model it is close to
it will identify
the point on which model
it will not identify
oh, am I going to wear shoes
or to wear a simulation model
so
when we are wearing boots
remember
don't add boots first
just put them
on the ankle
and then
select the fixing pin
and then right click
and then put all the fixing pins
on the simulation model
ok
then we can change the position
or wear shoes
and then
you have to pay attention
in our software
the shoes you downloaded on the official website
most of them
will be adapted
only adapted to the simulation model in our software
ok
if you are wearing shoes
then you can use
OBJ
to be a simulation model
ok
now
the position of our boots
inside is the fixing pin
because the fixing pin
fixed all the material
all fixed
on the model's leg
so
the material inside
will not be worn out
otherwise
like boots
it is
well
it has a lot of internal net
and
there will be some
problems with the net
to turn the hair line
if you want to wear
the material inside
it is very troublesome
so we usually
use the fixing pin
to fix it
on the simulation model
we can also change the position
or
just
fix it
in the 3D space
do you understand
and then
this
this glove
the glove
is what we used to
the one
in the motorcycle suit
the material
in the material
is
there
you can
download it directly
so let's talk about
the buckle
is very simple
if we insert it
insert it into the virtual model
or insert it into the accessory
it's all OK
as long as you don't
stick it on
the material
I use the water-water tool
here
for quick positioning
because
when you use the water-water tool
you click on the panel
it will directly
position it
and then
after positioning
remember to remove the attachment
because if it is attached
there is no way
to set
the thickness of the attachment
and then
manually
slide it
adjust it
ok
so
just now
I don't know
if you noticed
I changed the form of our positioning ball
from the world coordinate
to the regional coordinate
so
I will briefly talk to you
about the differences
between these coordinates
the screen coordinate
is based on
the current screen
and the current screen
so
the screen
is based on
the current screen
so
the screen
is based on
the coordinates of your current screen
what does this mean
I will talk about it here
the positioning ball
is based on
the screen coordinates
look
I choose a board
this coordinate ball
is what my current screen
is based on
it is like this
the few axes of the positioning ball
will not change
and
the second
is the regional coordinate
the regional coordinate
is
I
have
a model
or a board
that
was originally
applied
to
which world
it belongs
which world's coordinate system it is which world, for example, how to say, it is the version created in Marvelous Designer,
so its coordinate system must be the coordinate system of Marvelous Designer, so its coordinate system is the world coordinate system.
Then, like our three-dimensional software or other software, it has its own coordinate system, right?
So at this time, when I click on it, its coordinate system is its original coordinate system, understand?
This is the unit coordinate, so the unit coordinate is usually used to deal with some, for example, like the joint skeleton,
because the joint skeleton itself has its own coordinate system.
However, if you cut to Shift X, it will automatically open this unit coordinate,
and then deal with some other files in the three-dimensional software,
it is also to use this unit coordinate as much as possible, it will be more convenient,
because our center of rotation is this object.
The last one is the world coordinate, the world coordinate has nothing to say,
the world coordinate is in the Marvelous Designer,
your coordinate is always in the Marvelous Designer coordinate.
Okay.
Then here, in order to facilitate the rotation of this file, I switched to the part coordinate,
so that when we rotate, we will not feel some trouble, it will be a little more convenient.
Then adjust it, let it go through,
and then it's done.
Then sometimes if your fabric can't hang the model,
then first put your fabric of the physical shape,
ah, no, first put your fabric of the bending strength,
can give it a little higher,
that is, these two small fabrics,
their bending strength can be increased a little,
then the particle diameter of these two fabrics must be reduced.
Otherwise, if you have a lot of grid numbers in this model,
you have a very small grid number of this fabric, it can't hang.
Understand?
And then, if you have a lot of grid numbers in this fabric,
and then this model has a very small grid number, there will be problems.
Try to get them closer.
Can you understand?
Then, the model of the bending strength,
try to make their grid distribution even,
ah, don't have that kind of,
that is,
there are so many details,
and then there are so few horizontal details,
this is also easy to hang the board.
Um,
and then it includes some of the basic OBJs that you use as a scene guide,
it is also like this.
Okay, then we are,
this,
this.
This is the end of the content of the episode.
It's about these soldiers.
What problems do we have?
Or do you have any questions with our software?
Everyone can ask.
In the end, is this posture.
What I use is the copyrighted posture on our Coyo features.
You can download it directly.
So,
after watching this tutorial,
After watching this live broadcast,
including our sunglasses,
The sunglasses are also free to download on the official website, and the models are also free to download on the official website.
You can follow our tutorial, and the gloves are also free to download on the official website.
So as long as you follow our tutorial, you can make this set of clothes.
Okay, I want to see the little friends who come to watch the live broadcast today, give me homework next week.
What kind of software do you usually use?
Let me see what mode the outer model is going to fall into, so that it can be arranged like a package.
Do you say package, do you say this?
Do you say it?
Whether it's a virtual model or a copy, it can be stored in the Marvelous Designers 12.
Okay.
You can use the copy mode or the virtual model mode.
The virtual model can be stored in Marvelous Designers 11.
How do you do the red powder line?
Do you say this?
Oh, do you say this?
This is the name line.
Just use an editor name line tool here.
And then at that time, I directly locked all the outside lines of the version.
And then on all the internal lines, I added a frame like this one by one.
Okay, thank you for your support.
Thank you.
Actually, our live broadcast will really talk about a lot of things.
When I was preparing the pre-cut material, I will try my best to prepare it for everyone.
It's a very useful material.
So everyone must watch the live broadcast seriously.
Okay, I'll try my best to tell you as much as I can.
Including everyone, like before, everyone said that this animation won't do it.
We'll do an animation tutorial like this.
I also really hope that everyone can use our software quickly.
Because I know that everyone has a pretty high demand for our software.
Also, thank you all for your hard work.
Including that OYOKI.
Just support me like this.
Thank you.
Thank you for supporting us.
You have also persisted in this live broadcast for so long.
It's really not easy.
Actually, this outfit is really not very difficult.
It's more complicated.
But it's not the kind of clothes that are difficult in terms of skills.
So everyone, after watching the live broadcast today,
Next week, the recording will come out.
Also, friends who are watching the recording now,
You can try to do it.
If you want to do it, it's too hard.
The center point of the board is how to accurately align the middle axis.
You mean...
I don't understand.
Wait a minute.
Is that what you mean?
Is it the double center point?
Can I watch the previous live broadcast?
Yes, you can.
In the past, the live broadcast was on our Bilibili account.
You click on the attention and then click on it.
You can see it.
Or do you want to align it here?
Move to the center of the ground?
Oh, like this.
Do you want to do this?
I don't know.
Do you want to turn like this?
Like this?
Or do you just need to put it here?
And then put it in the center of the ground?
Move to the center of the ground.
The board is too small.
And then that place wants to add a fold.
Is it useful?
Yes.
You have to do this.
For example...
Wait a minute.
I'm going to use a new fabric for you.
For example, you want to add it in this position.
One is that you can use a ruler.
Use a straight ruler.
See?
You can add a fold here.
But in this case, the ruler itself is...
It has its own limitations.
You must pay attention when you add it.
Control the amount.
And then you can choose after adding it.
I can't remember the points.
How to do the back waist after the hanfu?
No fold.
If you buy a second pair of people, you can add three pairs.
How to do a no-fold fold?
Add a line.
Or...
It has something to do with your structure.
It has something to do with your model structure.
Actually, I'm afraid that people will ask questions about hanfu.
Because there are many things to pay attention to in hanfu.
But in fact, when you are making a model,
It's hard for you to restore it one by one.
You can't do that.
No fold in that position.
You see, like me.
I'll go along this direction.
Add some shrinkage to it.
And then...
It's not shrinkage.
I'll draw a turtle.
And then give it a small segment.
So that it has more fold.
Let me show you.
If we delete all the turtle.
And then delete all the segment.
It's actually very little.
Not a lot.
But you have to know.
Which direction are you folding in?
For example, I want to fold along this direction.
Then I draw the turtle must be so slippery.
I can't draw like this.
Do you understand?
If I draw like this.
What do I draw?
It's like this.
This fold is obviously not the fold we want.
So you have to have this concept.
In which direction do I add the fold?
Can't add.
In fact, it's a little bit like this.
I can't add it to this side.
Can the hand be exactly aligned?
You said this.
It should not work.
But I don't know why you must let it be exactly aligned with the y-axis.
Is it because you want this thing to be in the middle?
Because I think if you want to put it around the virtual model
The virtual model itself has a point of arrangement
Isn't it just in the middle?
Then if you want it to be flat
Then you just give it a point of arrangement from here
Then move it to the center of gravity
It's also possible
If you want to change the direction of the fold, is there a way?
No, you have to change the board
Add a little more
Yes, you either add a little more or change the board
You have a fold, you think about it
Sometimes you pull
This fold
You are pulling this fold in this way
If you want it to be oblique
Then you can only do this
If you want it to fall, you can only do this
You can't do this
And also violate this physical
Physical common sense of the fold
You know
It's hard
If you have any problems, you can also add our Q group
Now there are still places in the third group
If you have time for the second group and the first group, you can also add
But you don't have to add too many groups at the same time
Because in fact, the groups are not much different
So you still have to do it first
Is the regular basic version
Then it's more convenient to add a fold in the direction
If you just do it
You do it very wide and big
Just
Your fold is a little more difficult to control
Proceed gradually
A little bit
Okay
If you don't have any questions
We can see you next time
Or see you in the next tutorial
You can remember to add us
This B station's attention
And follow our live broadcast
Or wechat account Marvelous Designer
Or add our QQ group
We usually live broadcast
Or send tutorials
Talk on these channels
There is also Weibo
Weibo Marvelous Designer
You can pay attention
Thank you for your support
Thank you for watching so late
Watch the live broadcast
Thank you all
If you have a group number, you will see it in the back of your private message
Just send us this account
You can see it
Thank you for your support
See you next time
Bye bye
Not every Friday live broadcast
No no every Friday
Don't come next Friday
See next Friday
There must be no live broadcast
Not every Friday
Thank you for your support
Bye bye
Good night
Thank you for your support
I hope today's content can help everyone
See you next time
Bye bye